ladies and gentlemen good evening and a
very warm welcome to the ICI Lombard
General Insurance company limited's Q3
and 9mon fy2 24 earnings conference
call from the Senior Management we have
with us today Mr sanjie mantri MD and
CEO of the company Mr gopal balachandran
CFO and
cro Mr alok Agarwal executive director
Mr Girish nyak Chief technology and
health underwriting and
claims and Mr sandip Goradia Chief
corporate solutions
group please note that any statements or
comments are made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being
expressed as a reminder all participant
lines will be in the listen only mode
there will be an opportunity for you to
ask questions after the presentation
concludes should you need assistance
during this conference please signal an
operator by pressing star and then zero
on your Touchstone
phone I now hand the conference over to
Mr sanjie mant
MD and CEO of ICICI Lombard General
Insurance Limited thank you and over to
you sir thank you good evening to each
one of you thank you for joining the
earnings conference call of icsa Lombard
for quarter 3 and 9 month Financial year
2024 I would like to wish you and your
family a great 2024
ahead while we had a brief intruction in
the last quarter I'm happy and excited
to engage with you all in my new role
I would like to take the first few
minutes to share my vision on the
journey ahead for our
company I firmly believe we're in the
midst of exciting times both as a
country and as an
industry India is expected to be the
fastest going economy globally Insurance
sector is our in the country continues
to provide a multi-decadal growth
opportunity supported by the regulatory
commitment to enable insurance for all
by
2047 in my view this will unleash
tremendous positives for the industry in
time to
come as a company we will continue to
create newer value tools in the industry
and maximize our participation in the
existing ones and I believe we can
achieve this through our vision of one
aisle one
team now let me give you a brief
perspective on our vision of one is one
team over the year the company has
created multiple functions
SCH to access various business
opportunities available this was an
approach which worked well for us in
that phase of a journey however the
present scenario is fast evolving and
dynamic due to which the existing way of
functioning inhibites us from leveraging
the combined strength of the
organization keeping this in mind we
have decided to bring a conscious shift
in a core philosophical approach we and
we aim to transcend functional silos and
convert the entire organization into a
United Team working towards a single
organizational purpose simply put it
implies when icsa Lombard WIS everyone
wins this will be a cold cultural anchor
and every decision that we take whether
strategic or tactical will be guided by
this I'm excited to share that we have
already taken early steps to align our
organization to this in letter and
spirit however as we embark on this
journey we will continue to focus on
Market opportunities and leverage our
existing distribution Channel we have
over the years followed a customer
Centric approach and will continue with
our overarching philosophy of balancing
growth and
profitability let me now give you a
brief overview of the industry Trends
and developments that we have witnessed
in the past few months post this our CFO
Mr gopal balachandran will share the
financial performance of the company for
the quarter and 9 months ended December
31st
2023 domestic GDP grew by 7.6% during
quarter ended September 30th 2023
indicating strong growth primly driven
by the government infrastructure push
healthy balance sheets of Banks and
corporates improving business sentiments
and rise in public and private capex
should boost boost CeX activity going
forward broader economic activity
indicators like GST collection eway
bills generation manufacturing PMI non
food credit growth indicate robust
demand in the economy however the heads
for domestic growth can emerge from weak
external demand typ Financial conditions
and geopolitical
tension as we speak India is globally
the fastest growing auto market and the
third largest in terms of sales volume
as per cm in 9 month 2024 new Private
Car Sales continued to have robust
growth despite the higher base with over
3.1 million Vehicles being sold mainly
driven by F festive
demand for 9 month
2024 13.5 million two wheelers were sold
also held by uptick in rural demand for
the full year the sales are expected to
cross pre-o
levels for 9 months Financial year 2024
1.2 million commercial vehicles were
sold this was driven by growth in insire
and other core sectors
health insurance continued to deliver
robust growth remaining the largest
contributor to overall industry
premium the commercial lines of business
witness growth in the line with commer
current market environment forther
private and public CS in investment have
led to robust growth in the engineering
line of business we expect the
commercial line segment to do well in
the future on back of overall economic
growth and capacity
creation Now speaking of the performance
The General insurance industry delivered
a Yi growth gross direct premium income
growth of 14% for 9 month 2024 excluding
crop and Mass health the growth is at
15.2% for the same period overall the
combined ratio of the industry was at
11.9% for H1
2024 as against 112. 2% for H1 2023
excluding the impact of areas for the
PSU
Insurance within the industry the
industry combined issue for motor
business for
119.4 for H1 of 2024 as against 123.5
for H1 of 2023 while the Improvement in
Combined ratio is directionally positive
it continues to remain at elevated level
further for 9 month 2024 the industry
has witnessed three catastroph events
which is expected to have an impact on
financial year 202 industry combined
ratio moving to business impact for us
in quarter 3 and 9 months for
2024 the company grew at 13.4% during Q3
of
2024 which was higher than the industry
growth of
12.3% for 9 month 2024 our growth was
16.5% again the industry growth of
14% I will now speak about a performance
in key business segments during the
quarter ended 9 month month Financial
year
2024 in the commercial line of business
we have developed strong capabilities on
the back of a unique distribution
franchise duly completed comp
complemented by our value added services
this Bas underwriting and large and
highly rated reinsurance capacities as a
result we have Consolidated our Market
position in this business over the last
decade during quarter3 Financial year
2024 we grew at 12.5% as an industry
growth of 13. 3% for 9 month Financial
year 2024 we have grown by 15.7% which
was higher than the industry average of
9.7% motor as a category has always been
a focus area for us as we speak for the
first N9 months we are the second
largest motor insurer for quarter 3 we
achieved an industry leading position in
this segment we have a robust reserving
philosophy which is demonstrated by our
reserving triangles and granular data
for our portfol folio decisions we'll
continue to leverage a strong multi-
distributional structure which enables
us to access the market along with the
best inclass claim servicing teams
focusing on superlative customer
experience for the motor segment in
quarter 3 we have registered a growth of
5.6% as against industry growth of 10%
for 9 months Financial year 2024 we grew
at 7.1% as against the industry growth
of
14.3% the growth in motor segment was
added by strong growth in the new
Private Car segment which view at 30%
for 9 months our two- wheer growth of 9
months 2024 was 14% which was higher
than the CM volume growth of
99.9% as the rural demand picks up we
hope to see the trend
continue the CV segment as we had
mentioned in our earlier call had no TP
price high for financial year 2024 and
consequently we focused on targeted
portfolio sourcing among the available
value pools for 9 month 2024 our mix of
Private Car two wheer and CV stands at
51.4
27.8% and 20.8%
respectively we also continue to build
efficiency in motor claims in quarter 3
2024 through our preferred partner
Network we have been able to service 67%
of our agency and direct claims up from
51% in quarter the financial year
2023 we are excited about the
opportunity in the motor segment and we
leverage all our existing capabilities
as one team to carry the momentum in the
coming quarter the health segment
contined to be the fastest growing
segment for the industry we grew faster
than the industry both in Q3 and 9
months registering a growth of 24.7% and
29.1%
respectively our health
business retail Health business grew in
line with the industry at 19.2% for 9
month
2024 to create a sustainable portfolio
we are focusing on preferred geography
and higher some insured our new business
grew at 24.5% during this period why we
why we will have likeed to grow faster
we will continue to invest by focusing
on preferred segment and new product
launches in the coming
quarter on Bank we have developed an
industry leading practice which
continues to be a strong pillar for our
company our bank insurance and key
relationship group grew at
13.6% for the quarter and 21.5% for 9
month
2024 we'll continue to deep mine our
existing Relationships by creating new
value streams which at the same time
focusing on acquiring a new relationship
within this
icsis within this ICA group distribution
view
19.9% for quarter 3 and 16.9% for 99
months onetop solution for all insurance
and wellness needs the IL take care app
has suppressed surpassed 8.5 million
user downloads till day we continue our
growth momentum with 1.6 million user
downloads for the quarter and during the
quarter Source premium was over 100
billion sorry 1 billion through this app
registered a 3.2x increased
Yi our digital business grew at 39.1% in
quarter 3 and 43% in 9 months and
constitut 6.6% and 5.8% respectively of
overall business numbers it would
continue to continue to be the key
growth driver for us as I look ahead I'm
personally very excited with this
opportunity and committed to creating
long-term sustainable value for all our
stakeholders now I would request gopal
to take you through the financial
numbers for the Recently concluded
quarters and 9 months thanks aiv and uh
good evening to all I will now give you
a brief overview of the financial
performance of the recently concluded
quarter and 9 months we have uploaded
the results presentation on our website
you can access it as we walk you through
the performance numbers gross direct
premium income of the company was at
rupes 17.3 billion in 9 months fi 24 as
against R 16.48% FY 23 this was a growth
of 16.5 % which was higher than the
industry growth of
14% excluding crop and Mass health gdpi
growth of the company was at
15.6% it was higher than the industry
growth of 15.2% in 9 months
f24 GDP was at 62.3 billion in Q3 f524
as against R 5 4.93 billion in Q3 fi23 a
growth of
13.4% this growth was higher than the
industry growth of
12.3% excluding crop and mass sales gdpi
growth was at 12% which was again higher
than the industry growth of 11.3% in 9
months
f24 our gdpi growth during the quarter
was primarily driven by growth in the
preferred segments the overall GDP of
our Property and Casualty segment grew
by 12.5% at 16 billion in Q3 fi 24 as
against 14.22 billion in Q3
fi23 on the retail side of the business
GDP of the motor segment was at rupes
as against rupe 26.91 billion in Q3 fi23
registering a growth of
5.6% the advanced premium numbers was
was at rupes 33.4 billion at 31st
December 2023 as against rupes
32.892880
five billion in Q3 fi23 registering a
growth of
24.7% our agent which includes the point
of sale distribution count was 1
12588 as on December 31 2023 up from 1ak
22461 as on September 30
2023 GDP of the retail Health segment
grew by 16.2% during the quarter 3 Group
Health segment grew by 27.2% during Q3
fi
24 as against last year where we saw no
major catastrophic events during the
year during this year we witnessed three
major catastroph Cyclone paperjoy North
Indian floods and Cyclone mun our share
of insured losses in these scat events
have been lower than our natural market
shares resultantly combined ratio was
103.7 for 9 months fi 24 as against 10
4.6% for 9 month
fi23 excluding the impact of cat losses
of rupes 1.37 billion in 9 month f24 the
combined ratio was
10.6% combined ratio was 103.6 in Q3 fi
24 as against 10
14.4% in Q3
fi23 again excluding the impact of cash
losses of .54 billion rupees in Q3 fi 24
the combined ratio was 10
12.3% our investment assets Rose to
rupes 4686 7 billion as at December 31
2023 from rupes 43.122762
for December 2023 as againsted 4.07
times as at September 30 2023 investment
income was at R 25.96 billion in 9
months f524 as against R 21.6 billion in
9 months f23 on a quarterly basis
investment income was at R 8.38 billion
in Q3 f524 as against rupes 7.66 billion
in Q3
fi23 our capital gains net of impairment
on investment assets stood at R 3.9 5
billion in 9 months
f524 as compared to rupes 2.94 billion
in 9 months
f23 capital gains net of impairment
investment ass stood at rupees 1.08
billion in quarter 3 fi 24 as against
1.52 billion rupees in Q3
fi23 our profit before tax grew by 20.6%
at rupes 18.5 57 billion in 9 months f24
as against rupes 15.4 billion in 9
months fi23 whereas PBT grew by 20 3.3%
Ates 5.74 billion in Q3 f524 as against
R 4.65 billion in Q3 fi23 consequently
profit after tax grew by 8.3% at rupes
13.99 billion in 9 months fi 24 as
against rupees
12.92% in 9 months fi 24 Pat grew by
32.4% at R 4.31 billion in Q3 fi 24 up
from rupes 3.53 billion in Q3
fi23 return on average Equity was 17.1%
in 9 months f24 as against 18.1% in 9
months fi23 the return on Equity average
equity for quarter 3 fi 24 was
15.3% as against 14.3% in Q3 fi23
solvency ratio was at 2.57 times at
December 31 2023 and againsted 2.59
times at September 30 2023 this
continued to be higher than the
regulatory minimum of 1.5 times as I
conclude I would like to reiterate we
continue to stay focused on driving
profitable growth sustainable value
creation and safeguarding interest of
policy holders at all times I would like
to thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we will now be happy
to take any questions that you may
have thank you we will now begin the
question and answer session anyone who
wishes to ask a the question may press
star and one on their Touchstone
telephone if you wish to withdraw
yourself from the question queue you may
press star and
two participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question ladies
and gentlemen we will wait for a moment
while the question que
assembles the first question is from the
line of kishan runta from MK Global
please go
ahead
kishan your line has been unmuted you
may proceed with your
question kishan runta your line has been
unmuted as there's no response from the
current participant we will proceed to
the next question which will be from the
line of Shrea
Shivani from clsa please go ahead thank
you for the opportunity uh
congratulation on a good set of numbers
I have uh two questions uh so firstly uh
excluding all the calamities that we
have seen in 9 month your combined ratio
has come at
102. 3% right and uh we had earlier
given a guidance to reach 102% by fi25
end so clearly a much better growth in
new vehicle sales has supported lower
loss ratios this year
uh so can you help us understand what is
your revised guidance for the next year
or next two years on the combined ratio
side given that uh we know that you are
currently investing in the health
portfolio and on technology front Etc so
that will be the first question and the
second question sir can you quantify the
loss ratio trend for retail health and
Group Health and uh there have been some
covid cases uh in the southern part of
the country how many cases do you have
is it something that we should be
concerned about for the fourth quarter
for the next quarter just trying to
understand if there's yet another thing
that hits Us in the next
quarter okay uh I think thanks
sh as far as the combin is show guidance
is concerned uh then uh gopal will share
with you in detail the loss issues that
you're seeking on the retail as well as
the group health side uh uh clearly uh
we stick to the guideline of what we
have mentioned that we will go to 102
over a period of time uh in terms of
revision clearly from an industrial
standpoint again we are
seeing ourselves placed reasonably well
but does this lead to make us believe
the guideline can go through a change at
this point we would say we hold to this
we want to see this trend holding up
over next maybe a quarter or two and
then we'll come back to the market if we
believe there's a revision uh to be done
on that uh in terms of retail and ghx
trending wise just we have seen uh
Improv M over what we had seen over last
quter go share the numbers in detail
yeah sh so I think uh so if you look at
the uh this is employer employee or
let's say the group health loss ratios
for quarter three of last year that
number was
98.9% this year quarter three that
number stands at about
93.1 uh on a 9month basis the again the
ghi loss ratios for last year was
95.9% 9 months of the current year that
number is at 95
5.8 on retail Indemnity again in the
same order Q3 last year was
68% Q3 this year is at
66% uh this is pretty much in line with
the range that we have been talking
about which is in the range of between
65 to 70% is the threshold that we are
comfortable with on the retail Indemnity
side and on the 9mon basis again retail
Indemnity loss ratios last year was at
65.2 this year we are at about
65.6% uh so that's the breakdown in
terms of the loss ratio across different
segments to your last point on uh covid
claims uh intimations I think too early
at this point of time we don't see any
specific uh instances or any spikes that
we get to see uh obviously we will watch
for the development but nothing uh at
this point of time for us to call out as
of now no cause of
concern okay sure and the overall
combined ratio guidance I get it right
that you may come back to us after maybe
a quarter or two if there's any change
in the guidance for now it's 102% for
fi25 yeah right now it's 102 we're not
seeing it but as I said seeing how the
other qu for will come back probably by
the year end sure sure this is useful
thank you so much thank you thank you
thank you the next question is from the
line of sankit godam from avendus spark
please go
ahead yeah yeah thank you for the
opportunity SJ we are seeing a little
better Trend in motor especially in the
month of November and December compared
to the industry so so just wanted to
understand that our strategy with
respect to motor has little changed
probably we are seeing little growth
coming back is it because of the pricing
environment changing or or we believe we
will be a little more uh aggressive or
or more confident to do motor than than
what we were doing in the past that's
that's my first question and and and on
similar lines uh again again in the
third quarter if I see you seems to have
grown Health ret Health especially at a
lower rate compared to the industry
despite doing Investments um we we
thought that you will grow at at least
1.2 to 1.3x of the industry your growth
seems to be broadly lower than the
industry marginally lower than industry
so I just wanted to understand uh why
the cautious stand being taken with
respect to on health or or is it because
of the competition on retail Health uh
that's on growth and and and and just
just on on gopal the question is motor
TP loss ratio uh uh see the number seems
to be again uh very good at around 62 U
and in third quarter or 65 in in 9
months so so typically we tend to uh
boost up the reserves in in fourth
quarter the historical Trend suggest so
so so so is it a case that we will see a
similar Trend or or you believe that 65%
motor T loss reported for 9 months will
will sustain for the entire year and and
similarly if you can com comment on on
the motor OD to whether whether this is
this is the number what we looking at
65 okay uh fair I will gopal will come
on the TP part I'll cover the motor what
is the trend that we are seeing and the
strategy going forward also on the
retail Health in terms of the uh numbers
which are relatively subdued which I
also said uh in my initial comment that
definitely would have wanted to grow
faster than that uh first thing on the
motor uh I think we continue to be a
very uh you know competent and uh
relevant player uh we saw in the past
also given that guidance that whenever
we have seen that kind of a market sh be
shaped up it was more conscious because
the
intensity uh what we thought would get
stabilized did not happen uh so we had
taken a step back and let it flow the
way it is now we have seen some of our
key competitors who are ruling in have
started uh putting lot more method in
that Madness and that has given us an
opportunity that being said quarter 3
typically has a tendency to have lot
more new sales in the season and there
we do uh end up with the structure that
we have having a lot more uh to you know
achieve as a team on motor overall on
market share but more importantly the
very critical Trend which can highlight
to all of you is that why why we had
been losing bit of a market share but
for the month of December we have gained
a market share of 10.7% 10.5 last year
in December so that Trend uh is a
critical one and we are well placed in
terms of what we believe if we see this
uh environment operating in AEM we will
not participate in any uh uh crazy hunt
if that's what the market leads to every
reason to believe there will be a bit
more of semblance and in that scenario
we will see ourselves exerting a lot
more in qu for in time to come so that's
what we have on Motor Trend broadly on
the retail Health subu number uh it's
it's not something which we are very uh
you know worried but yes we would have
led to grow faster we have taken certain
call in terms of someing sure which
category of portfolio rights because
again if you know whatever health book
that we write it is for a lifetime
usability technically and we need to
hold on to that customer we had certain
early Trend which got us concerned that
being said our new books has still grown
at almost 25% and we do believe that in
uh uh in time to come with the sort of
investment that we have done with our
human capital as well as the product
profile which will also happen over next
couple of quarters from our side we
would be a potent force and the and the
mission that we have shared is firmly on
track these are all conscious calls
which does not deter us uh in terms of
AV stand uh mot TP I ask gopal to answer
terms of the details that you had sh
s my I think our response will pretty
much be on the lines is what I have been
talking even in the past uh few uh
earnings call uh um so the range within
which motor OD loss ratios will operate
I think even last quarters we have been
talking about in the range of 60 to 65%
I think we pretty much stay on course in
terms of that part of the range on the
motor own damage side that's largely
because I think uh as an organization we
are kind of focusing a lot more in so
far as uh the claims initiatives are
concerned whether it is in the context
of uh the average claim size etc etc and
therefore to that extent I think the
range that we are comfortable with on
motor OD is in the range of 60 to 65 on
motor third party I think as we keep
saying uh again quarterly numbers may
not be the right way to look at but even
on a 9month basis I think the number for
US stands closer to about
65% there collect I think the range that
we have talked about has been in the
range of 65 to 70% but that again will
be a function of what kind of a risk
selection that we do and the point that
sanjie made I think clearly as an
organization we are significantly
focusing on much more uh granular of
data risk selection uh and so on and so
forth and therefore to that extent the
range that we would be kind of looking
at operating would be on third party
side between 65 to 70% which is why on
balance when you look at motor in the
aggregate that number should be in the
range of between 65 to 67% which if you
look at the 9 month numbers the motor at
on an aggregate basis the loss ratio
stands at about 65% for this year so the
range that we will be comfortable will
be between 65 to 67 on an aggregate
basis the only point I would say sankit
is uh in so far as there is no specific
trend line for us in so far as Q4 being
seeing any any form of aberration I
think possibly what you referring to is
maybe couple of years back uh this is I
think Financial year 2021 if I
recollected correct I think there was
certain Court Supreme Court judgments
that had come through in that particular
year and that's the reason why not just
for is Lombard even at an industry level
companies had to recalibrate their uh
ultimate loss experiences and therefore
to that extent one had to take some
impact of uh strengthening of uh losses
but otherwise it is not it is not
necessary that uh we do see any kind of
an inch up in so far as third party loss
experiences are concerned so far as
quarter 4 uh which you referring to okay
no no because I I saw a similar Trend in
fourth quarter ref 232 so so that's the
reason I was asking the question that
that 65 number is sustainable but you
answered that you're looking at a broad
number of 65 to 72 to play off for The
motoross
Rao sanj just just just to your comment
on
motor just wanted to understand you are
saying that in Market overall Market
competitive environment in motor OD the
relative madness has has come off and
and therefore Market is more conducive
than it was in the past that's the
conclusion I should make so I'll tell
you I think that will be a relatively
sharper conclusion but yes we do see
some bit of uh semblance uh overall and
the LR of the industry has gone down
from 93 to
and so if that is the indication yes
there's a Improvement but still if you
ask me from an overall standpoint uh the
industry is writing the motor
portfolio uh at a you know reasonable
triple digit of 118 119 so there is a
lot more that has to come off and even a
private sector is iting at 114 115 uh
it's a it's a long journey uh but what I
can tell you some is that where we stand
the lens through which we are looking at
the market they reasonably confident of
our practice and we will be able to
drive value for the organization uh uh
in the current environment that is
prilling uh but long-term trends have to
manifest you know that the industry
numbers come with a lag we are awaiting
uh the 9 Monon numbers for the industry
to get a sense which will be able to
give you uh closer to when the financial
year gets closed for us at that point of
time we can have a much more evolved
discussion on this subject perfect
perfect that's it from my thank you
thank you thank thank you ladies and
gentlemen in order that the management
can answer questions from all
participants in the queue we request you
to please restrict your questions to two
per
participant the next question is from
the line of mukar ladda from Nama wealth
please go ahead uh hi good evening uh
thank you for this opportunity and
congratulations for a good actually
underwriting performance uh clearly uh
you're you seem to be achieving uh your
guidance uh sooner than expected um so
just uh you know a couple of questions
uh on the motorite so I wanted to
understand uh with how is the
implementation of the entire loss
reporting uh within 6 months time uh
time period uh how is that progressing
and uh uh you know uh what is our sort
of expectation on that and related
question on this is uh is the industry
um you know in this uh uh uh sort of
believing that this will get implemented
and as a result of that the comparative
intensity had had had had been high or
uh or are they sort of looking because
you know they believe that the ultimate
loss ratios will be lower so is that uh
is that the correct way to think about
it or is that the way some industry
participants are thinking about it and
acting in in in that way and second
question on your investment yield that
seems to have dropped this quarter so
some understanding of what is actually
played out of there so uh those two
would be my questions yeah thanks sure
so I'll uh I'll let gopal come in and
I'll give my comments yeah goal yeah so
so maduk I think on the six months law
uh limitation uh I think as we have been
kind of uh indicating that matter still
U is before The Supreme Court and uh
obviously we will wait for let's say the
verdict to come out what we understand
is I think most of the states seems to
be in favor of getting the law of 6
months implemented and therefore to that
extent U I think one would obviously
wait and see how the final verdict plays
through but the the direction that
states want to take is clearly to kind
of get a law of limitation in place uh
having said that what could happen let's
assume for a moment that if it goes in
favor of let's say in line with the six
months law of limitation again the
impact could vary between players in the
market because at an aggregate level for
the market obviously there will be some
reduction in frequency as we have been
explaining consequent to reduction in
possible frauds so that's a positive in
so far as the overall Market is
concerned second I think in in in the
context of ICA Lombard obviously we have
been inflating uh reserves with an
inflation assumption for is H at between
12 to 13% this inflation assumption for
the market may not be the same and
therefore to that extent whenever this
will play out the impact could be
slightly more beneficial for companies
which have been reasonable in their
inflation estimations and for us as I
said we Isis Lombard has been inflating
at 12 13% Market if they have been
inflating at a slightly lower number
therefore to that extent the impact
could be relatively moderate for those
set of players so hence in that sense I
think it would obviously translate into
an incremental business opportunity for
us having said that this law of six
months limitation will be applicable
only on a prospective basis which is
effective from April 1 2022 so hence to
that extent uh is where we be able to
see as I said a relative benefit playout
for us in the context of the market uh
the other thing what could also happen
as a fif side to this is in case if
finally this law gets implemented there
is a possibility that next year or maybe
in future the regulator and the
government will very closely watch for
the need for any kind of a TP price
increase uh while last 3 four years
again we have not necessarily seen any
kind of a meaningful price change on the
third party side but given the fact that
this this six months law could lead to a
positive development from an overall
industry standpoint we may see periods
where we may not able to see further
increases on the third party pricing but
obviously that's a development that we
will again closely watch for in so far
as the third party uh six months law of
limitation Dynamics is concerned I'll
quickly answer the second question of
yours and then maybe I'll uh sanjie if
you wants to kind of add on uh so on the
investment uh yield again uh I think as
we have always said our realized return
is a function of what do we see as
interest approvals and uh what what is
it that we see as the capital gains for
us uh given the fact that we have been
significantly as we've been explaining
even in the earlier earnings calls the
high interest rate regime is something
that we have obviously taken advantage
of and hence to that extent if you would
have seen our yield to maturity on the
overall book that currently in fact at
December 31 stands at 7.31 % this number
if you recollect maybe couple of few
quarters back this number was less than
7% at about
6.92% so hence to that extent we have
actually been taking uh advantage of the
higher interest regime and that's kind
of aing well in so far as interest
approvals are concerned where in we
possibly see in some quarters possibly a
decline in yield is consequent to let's
say maybe relatively lower levels of
capital gains that's purely a function
of what we believe are Market
opportunities for any gain to be
realized we have generally not seen any
instance where we have seen uniform
levels of capital gains across quarters
so in fact there again I would urge
similar to the discussions that we have
been having on having on the loss ratio
side the yield on the overall portfolio
should be looked at again ideally over
on a financialized basis ideally over
longer years but definitely not on a
quarter on quarter basis so okay just to
add mukar in terms of the point that you
mentioned on TP directionally and we all
will agree that that even when became
part of Motor Vehicle act the adoption
at the state level would have always
gone through it sour but if the intent
is to make the overall consumer benefit
these things in spite of the hiccups I
believe over a period of time will get
implemented uh in a country like us it
will always be a little more complex uh
but multiple decisions which have been
taken by the body we remain positively
cautious and see that this will flow in
that direction over a period of time but
one bigger thing which I want add mukar
is the way I has come up the stream and
improve the quality of data sharing that
can happen at the industry level uh that
part uh has been transformative and the
level of accuracy and the the real time
manner in which we can think uh all of
the industry will benefit and we with
the uh with the level of you know
business that we do and that kind of an
accuracy I mean you know that banking
got transformed and Bureau came into
place and uh you could really figure out
where what stand BS and this data uh
once it gets created in the form will
also end up you know helping us figuring
out uh you know fraud and so on and so
forth so the base work has got done uh
to me that is also a big positive which
can benefit companies like a
substantially uh to drive efficient
equation in the
market thank
you just one question on the U
investment book uh what is the amount of
capital
gains this time around if you could give
that versus the last
quarter uh see the number of capital
gains for the quarter three was about
108 crores that is in that is in quarter
3 of this year as against 152 crores
which was the capital gains that we had
in quarter three of the last Financial
year and last quarter what was the
number sorry what are two numbers uh of
capital gain that number was about about
uh 164
CR okay
understood uh very clear thank you and
all the best thank you thank you thank
you thank you the next question is from
the line of prayes Jen from moil oswal
please go ahead uh yeah hi good evening
everyone uh just a few questions firstly
could you elaborate on your strategy
that you were talking about in our
initial opening remk
could you just elaborate on that new
that you talking
about yeah okay fair enough I'll do that
you have second question also you want
to say now which I can cover or we'll
come back once I reply on this no so the
second question was more on motor motor
business granularity as to you know
we've seen uh you know faster premium
growth with respect to as compared to
the vehicle growth and that's possibly
because of certain factors like
premiumization share of EV is going
higher CG share going higher top models
going higher or you know automated
Vehicles going higher uh any of these
cohorts where you think that the you
know particularly EVS where you know
your experience would have been kind of
uh uh you know much better than what you
would have expected earlier and you seen
some price Corrections out there or in
with respect to you know drive as you
use or the the pilot project that we
were working on earlier how is that mix
evolving I think some granularity on the
motor business will help us kind of look
forward into the future on on this
business and last question was on
commission ratio where you know how do
you see the commission ratio kind of
planning out this quarter it was at 17%
thereabout and so how do we look at this
ratio from a full year perspective uh in
this year as well as your good yeah okay
okay thanks P I think let me just give
you a quick perspective of one is one
team uh I think as I also mentioned when
I spoke earlier in my script uh the fact
that it's a core philosophy change uh
we've been in the business for last 22
years and obviously as an organiz we
have created multiple Center of
excellences uh and these departments
have gone on to deliver a lot more for
the organization than one could have
thought at the Inception level uh but
the time has come where we need to add
an overarching level will uh see that we
are able to derive value at a multiplier
level for the organization to give you
an example right we we had value added
Services which was being driven by us as
a company we have our own patent which
are registered uh to manage risk but
this value Services used to work more on
a project basis with the entities what
we have ensured is that we getting this
embedded with the organization at
multiple departments on the commercial
side to drive the impact uh another part
is on the data analytics side you know
the data Engineers we do uh we do have
that particular Department which was
running and quite effectively but it was
not embedded they used to operate on a
project basis what we have done is that
we've got ahead and got that department
working with business Chiefs to direct
reporting in terms of making it work so
there's lot of synergy benefits that can
be driven on this uh at multiple counts
we would be driving and cross leveraging
it uh our practice as we have always
mentioned on the corporate side has been
very extensive but our ability to
harness to even procure retail business
becomes a significant part of our
strategy it's not even cross cell it's
actually all embeded solution the bulk
of the products that we deal with are uh
you know naturally inclined towards
trary requirement whether it's smmes on
the commercial side or motor health is
the only discretionary product uh that
corporates IND in you will also see
product launches in time to come which
would be harnessing this opportunity
across the segment you large you've got
large presence but the Consol itics uh
approach that was required mind you but
the word of caution is it does not mean
that the dissecting of the market and
ensuring that the leverage on our
distribution will get diluted uh at any
point in time for us so that's my two
bit in terms of you know discussing one
is uh one team as a as a company now
coming on to the motor part of the
strategy as you see uh uh we have seen a
significant uh transformation uh I just
covered the Ed part of business which
you spoke about uh from an overall
industry penetration level it has moved
9 month the penetration was 3.5 it's
gone to almost
4.2 uh% for us uh we as a company have a
very dominant share on the EV side on
the private car which is the passengers
car we talking about we have a market
share of almost 18% and on two wheer we
have a market share of almost
28% uh we are obviously bullish and we
do believe that over next couple of
years we will have the infection Point
as the infrastructure which is required
to see this getting much more uh so two
points one infrastructure other the
price point which makes it workable uh
we would continue to invest and uh loss
ratio yes we do see that uh it's
relatively better but I would not rush
to conclude that as it because these are
very early days this will emanate over a
period of time uh but we'll stay
invested because this is the category
which can rule the market in terms of
overall motor uh clearly quarter three
new sales which you spoke about and
youve read those number that we have
seen a growth in private car of 30% in
two wheer by almost 14% much higher than
what the industry has done uh uh again
uh multiple things one we are well
equipped in terms of the new business as
in when that growth comes back our
ability to operate in a decisive manner
uh is pretty much their existing and uh
we we do uh uh believe
that this should exhibit over next uh
probably a quarter or so also but we
never expected the industry on the
private car to grow at a level of almost
7 7 and a half% because the base for
last year itself was high uh and India
has moved on to become the third largest
manufacturer of uh you know overall
Motor Vehicles which itself I think
speaks about how the volumes are getting
driven another big change which has
happened the SUV cars have started
dominating which is the average ticket
size is high so you would also see that
getting exhibited in a number as we
speak about the motor growth that will
come in so overall we remain uh positive
in terms of driving our motor initiative
uh as a team uh on the commission ratio
I'll ask gopal to just quickly give you
an update we've been pretty much within
the regulatory limit as prescribed and
qu see since the new vehicles are there
the express ratio t to be elevated
historically for the industry and more
so for us so PR I think again uh in line
with what we have been mentioning even
in the earlier earnings call I think a
better metric to look at as we keep
saying is combined ratios because there
will always be businesses which could be
high on LR and low on cost of
acquisition and the vi Versa as well uh
so hence to that extent I think one
would urge uh to continue to look at
more the uh combined ratios of the
company as a whole having said that I
think in line with what sanjie said if
you look at our expense of management
numbers at the percentage of gwp this
number for the N9 months last year was
at about 28.6% for the 9 months of
current year this number stands at about
28.1% so there has been some improvement
in the overall expense of Management
number but as I said a better metric to
look at is more the combined ratios for
the company as a
whole uh just just Sor we request you to
please rejoin the question Q for further
questions the next question is from the
line of nides from investtech please go
ahead uh thanks for the opportunity sir
first the health
insurance uh we have been investing in
that distribution uh for last almost two
years but still our growth has been
broadly in lined with industry or uh in
the month of December we laed industry
uh so what are the aspirations there and
when we think the the growth pick up in
the ret health insurance will be in our
yeah I think a very valid question n
again as I was mentioning given when I
was talking earlier in the call uh we
also uh would have preferred going
faster uh if you see our growth in
quarter one was uh quite higher than the
industry but we have taken certain calls
on the some insured as well as the you
know nature of new business that we want
to procure these are very finite
definite calls we are very pry much on
track in terms of uh what we want to
achieve uh our new business spite of the
call has gone by almost
25% uh as a company so uh if you ask me
where will we see a real you know growth
coming in this since this changes have
been done over quarter one and quarter
two you will see this playing out uh uh
very clearly over next financial year
and what we have spoken with the market
and probably three quarters back in
terms of the growth at that point these
calibration that we have done because we
felt um Health as a portfolio which
comes with lifetime relity requires
realtime calibration so we chose to take
that call at this point of time so that
the long-term value equation that we
want for the organization does not get
compromised uh but you will see our
convergence as a team not only in terms
of growth but also product launches uh
which are still uh if you ask us on a
score of 10 on product uh you know or
solutioning stack that we want to feed
on the health side we would probably be
6 and a half and there abouts over 10 as
a score so we have that distance to be
covered and that also will get done in
next couple of quarters so we are very
positive and we do see uh good value
creation coming uh from next financial
year
onwards n does it answer your question
yeah so secondly on the motor site our
profitability has improved quite well
and our loss ratios are tracking uh one
of the best that we have seen uh so why
don't we pedal we push the pedal on the
growth and uh start focusing on market
share Gams in that segment even the
profitability is quite good for us I
think n you have only answered the
question in terms of a we we we stayed
focused and we had some losses on market
share but we we decided to stick the
course and that's what we are doing at
this point of time uh some of the other
partners who were uh you know being
aggressive also ped down so it's a
combination of we stitching to the
course and as I was also stating uh that
December was the first month in which we
have seen a relatively better market
share in our mind uh we do believe that
quarter Force should hold good for us as
a
team okay thank you thank you that's it
from my thank you m thank you thank you
the next question is from the line of
ainash Singh from MK Global please go
ahead yeah good evening a couple of
questions uh the first one on Commercial
line I mean fire Marine engineering if I
look uh on a 9month basis the movement
yui in cim ratio is material now uh in
terms of natcat it would have kind of a
played out maybe a bit higher this year
but not material so now just question is
that is this sort of a clearance ratio
increase in the commercial line and
outcome of you know any sort of a
pricing uh detoriation at the industry
level or is it also or largely due to
the reinsurance price hike that industry
has seen so I mean some color on what is
driving this commercial uh line loss
ratio increase and if the factors that I
just mentioned you know the pricing
detoriation or price heke if they are
largely done this year and should
improve going forward next year that's
one second again going on health uh you
have I mean overall growth is reasonably
good uh growth is of course led by the
pricing as well as uh some kind of
volume growth yet uh the claims ratio at
the aggregate level of course if you go
segment by segment there could be some
difference but at a aggregate level CLA
still inching up now is this uh an
outcome of you know just the claims
inflation or also you know uh claims
frequency also sort
of reflecting some kind of a uh increase
year on year so two question thank you
yeah yeah so ainash uh um I think on the
first one on the commercial lines uh
pretty much in line with what you
mentioned which is primarily whatever
you see as change in the loss ratios
whether it is for fire engineering or
some of the key commercial lines the
large part of the change in the loss
experience is predominantly driven by
the impact that we have seen on account
of flood events uh so so and this year
unfortunately if you would have seen
which is what we put out also as a part
of the opening transcript I think the
aggregate impact that we have seen on
account of various catastrophic events
last year was about 28 cror
this year if you look at nine months we
are already that number is at about 137
clores a large part of it is of course
some of the commercial lines but maybe
the recent Chennai floods I would also
say we have also got a reasonably large
number of claims that is coming on the
retail side which is on the mot side of
the business as well but to stay with on
the commercial lines I think the a large
part of the loss ratio change is
predominantly driven by the impact that
we have seen on account of uh the
various flood events that we have seen
and not because of uh
any other reason in fact the overall
growth in the commercial lines
particularly on fire has pretty much
played out in line with what we have
been speaking even in the earlier
quarters as in to say that the price
drop consequent to the removal of the
iib rates has been broadly in that range
of 5 to 7% and which was largely offset
I would say by the increase in the
reinsurance rates that we had seen at
the time of negotiating the program at
the beginning of the year so hence to
that extent is where I think our the
growth for the overall Market has been
largely muted in line with what we spoke
even during the April call uh what will
happen in the next year's reinsurance
renewal program I think uh maybe I think
we will be able to come back with a much
better Insight when we announce numbers
on a full year basis in April because
that's the time when we would have
largely concluded the reinsurance
placement but otherwise on so far as the
aditional losses are concerned I think
there is nothing other than that see
some of the impact on catastrophic
losses uh related numbers to second
point on the health loss ratio I think
is it's pretty much which is why I think
in response to one of the earlier uh
earlier questions that had come through
is where we had kind of put out the
breakdown of the loss isues uh so so in
that sense there if you clearly see I
think the loss ratios are pretty much in
line with the range that we are
comfortable with which is just to kind
of rate rate Group Health loss ratios we
have generally talk spoken about it
being in the range of 94 95% that's the
number at which we have endered even the
the current 9 month numbers and Retail
health inity I think the range that we
have spoken about has been between 65 to
70% if you would have looked at the 9
month numbers again they pretty much in
line with the range that we have spoken
about um of course we do see
inflation uh uh and let's say possibly
at times increase in claim frequency
particularly let's say during Quarter
Two largely driven by monsoons and other
related
seasonality but that's something again
like what I mentioned on motor where we
actively engage in kind of driving the
PPN initiatives uh on the motor site for
example we would obviously want to drive
a large part of the motor accidents to a
preferred network of garages the same
thought process is what we have even on
the health side which is to kind of we
have a separate Network management team
which significantly looks at focusing on
driving a lot more traffic to a
preferred network of hospitals where we
are not only able to guarantee so far as
the policy holders are concerned quality
of care which is very very important for
us
and more importantly an outcome which is
let's say a possible reduction in the
average claim size and thereby which is
how we are able to kind of manage the
possible change that we see on inflation
SL frequency and but on an overall basis
I think we are comfortable at the range
at with the loss experiences is playing
out okay thank
you thank
you the next question is from the line
of supratim data from Ambit Capital
please go ahead
thanks for the opportunity my first
question is on the new strategy of one
is one team so could you help me
understand what would be the impact on
the top line from this strategy and what
would be the would this also have a cost
impact in the form of cost savings
that's my first question my second
question is on the reinsurance so
globally if we see the reinsurance rates
uh you know this year at first gen has
gone up somewhere between 30 to 50% what
are we expecting here in India given F
you know cy23 so number of netcat events
which were higher than what we had seen
in
cy22 so uh that's my second question and
lastly I would just like to understand
kindly that that now that you know the
growth has returned on the motor side
what is the market share that you have
now within you know the uh Private Car
segment or the two- wheeler segment and
the commercial segment if you could help
me with that that help thank you okay
sure so on the uh one one team part in
terms of the top line as well as the
cost I think it will get Ed in what
gopal said we combined issue and what we
are able to deliver as a team uh uh we
have taken certain initiations in terms
of what we have done structurally uh if
we be early days for us to quantify
anything of that uh to the market you
will see that getting exhibited in time
to come we believe that we rather do it
than announce that this is what we
believe uh will get transpired but
clearly what I can assure you is we do
believe there is a kicker available as
on the top line as well as bottom line
on account of what we are pursuing as a
team so that's where it is on the
reinsurance part uh I ask go to just
give an update we don't expect the
premiums to runov we do have a guideline
we say 5 to 7 7 and half% thereabout is
what you expect to come in but it will
all get probably called out in specific
over quarter 4 gopal yeah yeah so I
think uh just to kind of suim I think as
I said uh so I think we are in the midst
of uh the negotiations in so far as
renewing the reinsurance program is
concerned and as I mentioned I think we
will be able to give you a much better
Insight when we kind of announce numbers
for the April uh April call uh is when
we would have stitched in the
reinsurance uh program and the rates for
the next year
but the initial indication seems to kind
of unlike last year where we had seen a
significant increase in the cost of
reinsurance for protecting the uh the uh
net retentions or let's say the X cost
that we are seen for producting
catastrophic uh event related losses our
sense is obviously the hike may not be
as much as what we had seen last year
exact numbers I think as I said I will
come we will be able to come back and
give you much better Clarity when we
announce numbers in April that's from
the re Insurance side to your point on
market share within let's say the new
market share for private car and uh two
wheelers private car we have a market
share of roughly about 12% around uh
that range and on two wheelers uh the
new market share has been uh currently
in the range of about 22% this of course
is slightly lower than what we would
have normally had I mean in the past
maybe our market share could on the
private car side would have been Higher
by almost about 3 4% and even on two
wheeler almost at a similar level I mean
you would have been we have always been
saying that on on new two wheelers one
in four uh one in four two wheer sales
is a a policy I so to that extent this
is pretty much in line with what we have
seen over the last two years where we
have lost a market share but as sanjie
indicated I think the momentum for us as
we speak looks to be very very strong
and positive and which is why if you
look at some of the quarter three or
month of December numbers the Head Start
that we're getting into in Q4 and
thereafter seems to be very very
positive for us and that's what we are
very optimistic and hence to that extent
uh even in the earlier earnings call if
you recollect what we had said was uh
motor we should see on an aggregate
basis growth coming back uh in line with
the market the early Trend seems to
indicate that in fact for the month of
December just to rate rate we have
actually had an outperformance relative
to the industry growth of
8.8% thank
you thank
you
ladies and gentlemen due to pity of time
we will now take the last question from
the line of Ashish Sharma from enam
Asset Management Company please go
ahead yeah hi uh thanks for the
opportunity uh uh just one question on
on similarly on the combined ratio uh
given that we are trending better than
uh uh uh in terms of improvement in
Combined ratio uh so can I mean if if as
you mentioned that you will take another
quarter sort before you would want to
change the guid but just wondering now
is there a possibility now that the
business can operate at a combined ratio
of 100% or below I mean given that we
seeing some sort of
a so uh I think fair question as from
your perspective but as things stand one
we'll discuss this probably by next
quarter as to where we are see because
we still want be overall trend coming
out in a consolid we don't want to jump
the gun while the early signs do look
better for us
but the sort of opportunity that we have
as a company we will continue to invest
so I would be very honest uh that uh SI
investment we can be where we are but uh
and the industry combin overall still at
112% so you know there are structural
changes and my firm belief is which I
can Shar with you we would love to see
industry itself improving in a
significant way because today well
industri is there is they're able to
performance X the whole industry
improves suly I don't see any reason why
IC Lumbard can drive far better benefit
out of it so we are operating both
industry level as well as the company
level uh to make an impact uh but uh for
a company like us and the opportunity
which I said in my opening remarks again
is significant so we would definitely
use some percentage of what comes our
way to reinvest to ensure that we have
Future Ready in terms of the opportunity
that comes uh would not jump the gun to
call out and say 100 is what it is it
will be a mix of things health will
continue SE more investment from us
because uh we have reasonable
competition as well as opportunity you
know being made available to us uh and
similarly on the digital space we'll
continue to do what is required to
harness our own uh ambition of where we
want to be so with all that in mind uh
uh I don't want to you know close seem
that is what it would be but let's
discuss this when we are there on the
April in the
call thank you yes yeah ladies and
gentlemen due to paity of time that
would be the last question for today I
now hand the conference over to Mr
sanjie mantri for closing comments over
to you sir uh I think uh thanks so much
I think the call has gone beyond the
distance but absolutely enjoyed
interacting with each one of you and
look forward to uh uh catching up with
each one of you in time to come we stay
positive and we do believe that we have
a great set of colleagues operating in
this segment with very very extensive
experience and we would definitely do
what is required to you know add further
value to the company in terms of the
industry which gives us tremendous
opportunity thank you so much and have a
great 2024 and see you
soon thank you
on behalf of ICICI Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited that concludes
this conference thank you all for
joining us you may now disconnect your
lines